<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Frank Muraca</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Frank Muraca</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>CHASR (Shiny App) North Carolina - like the rest of the nation - faces an affordable housing crisis. There are only 43 affordable rental units for every 100 extremely low-income households. In addressing their affordable housing challenges, local governments are required to make important decisions about where to allocate resources: Should policies target renters or homeowners? Are elderly or family households more impacted by rising housing costs? What does affordable mean?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measuring NC job loss from Covid-19</title>
      <link>/2020/04/16/measuring-nc-job-loss-from-covid-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/04/16/measuring-nc-job-loss-from-covid-19/</guid>
      <description>Over the past four weeks, more than 20 million people have filed for unenmployment.
In mid-April the Urban Institute released new estimates of the number of low-income jobs (&amp;lt;$40k salary) lost as a result of Covid-19. The estimates rely on three sources of data - the BLS, Washington State Employment Security Deparment, and 2017 LODES data - to predict job loss counts for every census track in the US. Washington State publishes weekly unemployment claims by industry sector and are used for this analysis until the BLS releases national unemployment figures by industry in May.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 21:48:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi! My name is Frank Muraca. I started this blog to write more about issues related to affordable housing policy, community development, and finance. I&amp;rsquo;m an analyst with UNC&amp;rsquo;s Development Finance Initiative (DFI), where I work with local governments across North Carolina address their real estate and economic development challenges, with a special focus on finding ways to build and preserve affordable housing. I work with data a lot at my work, so a lot of these posts will profile ways planners can learn more about their communities using R, an open-source software that let&amp;rsquo;s you manipulate and visualize different sources of information.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>